

YANZHEN LUO Fogedmarken 10, 2200, Copenhagen +45 7135 3893 yvetteluodk@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/yvette-luo/

PROFILE

I am Yanzhen (Yvette), a social data scientist with a background in Social Data Science and Economics, bringing strong data science skills and extensive research experience.

EDUCATION

MSc in Social Data Science University of Copenhagen	Sep. 2021 - Jun. 2023 Copenhagen, Denmark
Bachelor of Economics Peking University	Sep. 2015 - Jun. 2019 Beijing, China
Dual Degree: Bachelor of Laws (International Politics) Peking University	Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2019 Beijing, China

WORK EXPERIENCE

Insight consultant

Dec. 2023 - present

Will & Agency Copenhagen, Denmark

- I participated in a global protein market consulting project, utilizing social media data to extract valuable insights. I conducted both qualitative and quantitative research, including *social network analysis* and *co-occurrence analysis*, adeptly tailoring methods for international markets.
- I participated in a global bread consumer consulting project, focusing primarily on qualitative research. I connected with respondents to explore their bread preferences, extracting insights from individual *interview data*, and analyzing factors such as country, gender, and generational differences.

Research Assistant - Database Management

University of Gothenburg

May. 2024 - Jul. 2024

Gothenburg, Sweden

• I involved in a research project to create a data warehouse for Food Environment and Health based on Statistics Sweden and other platforms. I collected data from Statistics Sweden and other platforms using *APIs* by Python and R, managed the *Git database*, performed analyses, and wrote a literature review.

Research Assistant - Blockchain and Web 3.0

Jan. 2023 - Jul. 2023

Chinese University of Hong Kong

remote

• I specialized in data analytics using Python to provide insights into venture capital and the financial performance of blockchain-related companies. I applied financial knowledge and quantitative approaches, such as *regression analysis*, to a wide range of complex problems, and arrive at tangible conclusions.

Teaching Assistant - Coding Cafe

Sep. 2022 - Jun. 2023

University of Copenhagen

Copenhagen, Denmark

• I actively assisted students in mastering statistical concepts and overcoming coding challenges in Python and R, troubleshooting issues related to *API or web data collection, supervised learning*, and *data visualization*. This role required not only strong technical proficiency but also effective communication skills and patience, as I collaborated closely with diverse individuals to help them achieve their programming goals.

Research Assistant - Computational Social Science

Jul. 2019 - Jul. 2021

Peking University

Beijing, China

• I performed in-depth analysis of social media and medicine-related data using *machine learning* and *social network analysis* methods with Python and Stata. This role showcased my skills in data mining, statistical analysis, and attention to detail. It also demanded a profound curiosity for understanding complex social phenomena.

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

Research Project: Exploring the Influence of Food Environment on Health in Sweden | *Python* ongoing Research project, University of Gothenburg

Global Insights on Packaged Bread: A Mobile Ethnography Study in the global market ongoing Consultant project, Will & Agency, Novonesis

Global Insights on Lactoferrin: A Comparative Study in the US, UK, and China | *Python* Spring 2024 Consultant project, Will & Agency, Novozymes

Analyzing Sentiment Shifts During Cryptocurrency Market Volatility | *Python* Summer 2023 Master thesis, University of Copenhagen

Exploring Carbon Credit Creation from Meals Saved by Too Good To GoSummer 2023

Course project, University of Copenhagen

Data Governance in the Context of Polypoly: Legal, Ethical, and Political Dimensions Summer 2022 Course project, University of Copenhagen

HONORS AND AWARDS

Danish Government Scholarship

Sep. 2021 - Jun. 2023

Recognition for top students from non-EU/EEU countries

Excellent Graduate Jun. 2019

Recognition of students' exceptional academic achievements and contributions within Peking University

Excellent Graduate Jun. 2019

Recognition within Yuanpei College, Peking University

Merit Student Oct. 2018

Recognition of students' exemplary academic performance and leadership within Peking University

Academic Scholarship Apr. 2018

Merit-based scholarship within the Economics Department, Peking University

Merit Student Oct. 2016

Recognition of students' exemplary academic performance and leadership within Peking University

SKILLS

Languages: English (Fluent), Chinese (Native), Danish (A2)

Programming: Python, R, Stata

Document Creation: LaTex, Excel, PowerPoint, Markdown, Tableau

ABOUT ME

Living in Copenhagen since 2021, I've explored 16 European countries. I'm drawn to Europe for the openness, inclusiveness, and interesting cultural experiences. Prior, I lived in China and exchanged to Japan and South Korea, sparking my passion for diverse cultures.

My diverse interests encompass technology and social science. I believe in extracting valuable lessons from the past, even in the digital age. Programming serves as a tool to explore the world, and social science empowers us to understand and shape the current and future state of the world.